Hello friends,
welcome to the investing club. Today we will tell you
about ICICI General Insurance Company.
What does this company do?
What is its business model? So friends, let's
start the video.
Before we learn about ICICI General Insurance, what do you have to do? What
is insurance? It is
a contract between the insurance company
and the insurance company. There is an
agreement between the insurance company and the insurance company. Now, let's assume
you insure your vehicle.
What happens in this is that
a contract is made between you and the company. In this, the
insurance company charges you a premium of Rs. 610
for a certificate. If your vehicle gets
damaged in any way, the
company bears the cost.
What happened in this is that there was
a contract between you and the company.
Now let's talk
about the business of ICICI General Insurance. There are
two types of insurance. One is
life insurance and the other is general
insurance. Under life insurance, you insure
someone's life and you insure it, for example,
you insure your life.  If you have
taken insurance and you die
or if you have
life insurance for an animal and it dies,
then in that case the insurance
company gives you money. Now let's talk
about general insurance.
Except for life insurance, all other
types of insurance
come under general insurance. In this,
your car, home, travel, health, the smallest
insurance
comes under general insurance. The insurance of which is done by
ICICI Lombard General Insurance
Company.
It is the largest private general
insurance company in India. Apart from this, it is the
fourth largest and the 15th largest non-life
insurance company in the world. So friends, let's now
talk about where the company's revenue
comes from.
50% of the company's revenue comes from the air and motor segment.
This and the inter-match premium is 26 percent of the company's revenue from this
and
24 percent of the company's revenue
comes from third party insurance. Friends, there are two types of motor insurance.
One is Audi, know-how and the other
is Third Party Insurance. What happens in Audi? For example,
suppose you have your  If you have a car
insurance policy, then if
your car meets with any kind of
accident or you get injured, then the
insurance company gives you compensation for all this.
You have to pay the off-
charges there. And what happens
in third party insurance is that if there is some
damage to your car, then you
cannot put your name in it, in this, it is caused by
some other party, then
in that case, the insurance company
gives it. Friends, third party
insurance is very important for your car. For example, if
you are
driving a car and someone gets injured, then
you may have to pay compensation worth lakhs and crores of rupees. That is why
I say that if you do
not have your back value third party insurance, then get it done.
Now after this,
its third segment of loans comes from
health and travel, from this the company gets 22%
revenue. Those who get their health insurance, there is a
medical emergency etc., if
your health deteriorates somewhere, etc.  If this happens, then all
these are insured, you
can get ICICI Lombard General Insurance. Now, this company has
health insurance.
After this, the next
time comment is that you get insurance for your house from that amount,
so in
all this which comes under air fire insurance, the
company has a sixteen percent share in it.
Three percent of the company's revenue
comes from marine, this means that there are big
containers etc., when
they carry their goods from one place to another,
then
this company insures them, from here the company gets
three percent revenue.
Apart from this, there is other insurance from which the company gets
almost nine percent revenue.
Apart from this, the company
also does insurance in the agricultural sector.
Insurance in the agricultural sector means that if you are a
farmer and are doing farming, then you definitely get
your crop insured, so
this company does its work. The company is incurring
losses in the field of agricultural insurance. If the company is charging ₹100, then a lot of money is lost.
11.4 rupees is what
APE is doing, so friends, now let's talk about
what the future holds for this company,
friends, the insurance business is a very
good business, there has been a
situation of self-entry recently, after this people are getting
paid for their health insurance and other types of insurance,
they are wanting to spend as much as possible on medical things, due to this the
market share of this company is
likely to increase, right now very few
people get health insurance,
and where we have almost no, right now
due to the situation of Covid-19, the company's losses have increased
because due to the use of Covid-19,
its revenue will be affected, along with this,
people are at home, people do not have any work,
due to this people do
not want to spend much money on motor insurance etc., this will also
affect its revenue, friends, I
hope you liked this information, if you liked it then
definitely like it,
friends, if you also  If you
invest in the share market or
want to invest and are looking for a good broker,
then you can open your account with India's most trusted Rokda
Egg Security.
You will not be charged any brokerage charges in this
and if you do intraday trading then
you will have to pay a maximum
brokerage charge of Rs. 10000 only. Apart from this,
if you
open your account through the link in the description given below,
then you can also get a cashback of up to Rs. 10000.
Thank you.